{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The gram-negative organisms is", "opta": "Actinomyces", "optb": "Bacillus", "optc": "Clostridium", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Catalase production is negative in which of the following?", "opta": "Streptococcus", "optb": "Salmonella", "optc": "Proteus", "optd": "Staphylococcus", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a substitute for crystal violet used in gram-staining procedure?", "opta": "Methylene blue", "optb": "Bromocresol green", "optc": "Safranin", "optd": "Phenolpthalene", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following inference(s) indicate(s) the ability of an organism to utilize citrate as a sole source of carbon in Simmon's citrate medium?", "opta": "Blue colour", "optb": "Appearance of growth", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organisms that can be acid-fast stained is", "opta": "Nocardia", "optb": "Tubercle bacilli", "optc": "Lepra bacilli", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The primary stain of Gram's method is", "opta": "safranin", "optb": "phenolpthalene", "optc": "crystal violet", "optd": "methyl red", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At what concentration of sulphuric acid, Nocardia resists decolourization?", "opta": "0.5% sulphuric acid", "optb": "5% sulphuric acid", "optc": "10% sulphuric acid", "optd": "8% sulphuric acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is commonly used as Gram's decolouriser?", "opta": "Ethyl alcohol", "optb": "Methyl alcohol", "optc": "Acetone", "optd": "A mixture of ethyl alcohol and acetone", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Production of acetoin can be detected by which of the following tests?", "opta": "Citrate test", "optb": "Voges-Proskauer test", "optc": "Methyl red test", "optd": "Indole test", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The production of sufficient acid by fermentation of glucose leads to decrease in pH such that pH of the medium falls below 4.5. Which of the following test can detect it?", "opta": "Indole test", "optb": "Methyl red test", "optc": "Citrate utilization test", "optd": "Voges-Proskauer test", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the colour of gram -postive bacteria on a gram staining?", "opta": "Purple", "optb": "Pink", "optc": "Colourless", "optd": "Green", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the colour of gram-negative bacteria on a gram staining?", "opta": "Purple", "optb": "Pink", "optc": "Green", "optd": "Colourless", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a primary stain for acid fast staining of mycobacteria?", "opta": "Crystal violet", "optb": "Carbol fuchsin", "optc": "Geimsa", "optd": "Methylene blue", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The deinococci are gram-positive cocci and rods that are distinctive in their unusually great resistance to", "opta": "radiation", "optb": "desiccation", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "extreme temperatures", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following shows a positive urease test?", "opta": "Proteus", "optb": "Klebsiella", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/ are oxidase-positive bacteria?", "opta": "Vibrio", "optb": "Neisseria", "optc": "Pseudomonas", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the order of reagents used in the Gram stain?", "opta": "Crystal violet, iodine, safranin, decolorizer", "optb": "Crystal violet, iodine, decolorizer, safranin", "optc": "Safranin, crystal violet, decolorizer, iodine", "optd": "Crystal violet, safranin, iodine, decolorizer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Gram staining was developed accidentally in 1884 by", "opta": "Alexander Fleming", "optb": "Hans Christian Gram", "optc": "Joseph Christian Gram", "optd": "Robert Gram", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following organisms can be demonstrated with silver impregnation method?", "opta": "Vibrios", "optb": "Salmonella", "optc": "Spirochaetes", "optd": "Shigella", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) show(s) positive results for phenylalanine deaminase test?", "opta": "Providencia", "optb": "Proteus", "optc": "Morganella", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of Gram staining is based on the ability of bacterial cell wall", "opta": "to retain the safranin dye", "optb": "to retain the crystal violet dye during solvent treatment.", "optc": "to retain part of both dyes", "optd": "none of above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}